# RICHARD D MADISON - FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

West Chester, PA 19382 | 610-761-4397 | rick.madison.58@gmail.com | Linkedin | GitHub

# SUMMARY

Full-Stack software engineer proficient in using JavaScript for front-end and C# for back-end programming, React, HTML, CSS, jQuery, API implementing, Node.JS, ASP.NET MVC, SQL Server, Bootstrap, and Agile. Experience as varsity ice hockey coach provides advantages in communication, organization, and teamwork.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, iQuery, Angular, Bootstrap Backend: C#, Node.js, Express, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL, SQL Server

Design & Concepts: Object-Oriented Analysis & Design (OOAD), MVC, Agile, Waterfall, Scrum, Schemas, SDLC

Tools: Mocha, Chai, Knex, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Node Package Manager, Visual Studio Code

# SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROJECTS

#### Certificate, Software Engineering | Thinkful | Online

08/2022 - 01/2023

#### Movie eCommerce Application | Link

- Assembled the back end of a movie website allowing any user to search for tickets for their favorite movie.
- Used CRUD methods for reviews, and view theaters and movies that are showing.
- Applied router and controller functions to retrieve a user's specific requests.
- Technology: C#, ASP.NET MVC, SQL Server, JavaScript, and AWS. Version control with Git.

#### Library Application | Link

- Assembled the functionality for an application that allows users to search, review and check out books from their local neighborhood.
- Created search and sorting functions to allow users to know what books were available and their rating. Coded using JavaScript to enable the expansion of the library with little to no need for code refactoring.
- Technology: JavaScript ES6, Bootstrap, HTML5, Node.js

# Study Tool Application | Link

- Created an application that allows users to create, edit, and delete decks and cards within them.
- Created a REST API and middleware functions to allow user(s) to create, read, update, and delete their perfect deck of study cards.
- Defined routes and URLs and used state over multiple components.
- Technology: JavaScript, React, Express, Knex, HTML and CSS, Progress/Versions tracked with Git.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NewRez LLC Fort Washington, PA Mortgage Underwriter 12/2020 - 07/2022

- Ranked in top ten of over 160 underwrites in both units and efficiency for nine consecutive months.
- Exceed monthly goal by 66.7% each month with a 100% funding accuracy.

Princess Daliana Sales Manager, North America

Wilmington, DE 03/2020 - 12/2020

Recruited two largest retailers in company history tripling units sold each month.

Increased sales revenue by 200% during COVID-19 lockdowns.

# Envoy Mortgage **Operations Manager**

Newtown Square, PA

06/2013 - 03/2020

- Oversaw growth in team of 400% during an increase in volume of 600%.
- Responsible for training, development, and management of staff funding more than 40 mortgages per month.

# **EDUCATION**

# Thinkful Certificate, Software Engineering

Online

08/2022 - 01/2023

- Learned industry best practices and software development standards with a focus on JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React Native, Node is, PostgreSQL, RESTful API's, algorithms, and data structures.
- Developed and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks, collaborating with, and learning from senior web developers in a mentor-student relationship.

Widener University Chester, PA May 2009